Contact

+359893022848 (Mobile) tonigashi999@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tonigashi (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

React.js TypeScript Node.js

Languages

Albanian (Native or Bilingual)
Bulgarian (Limited Working)
English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Amazon DynamoDB Service Primer Network Ninja to Cloud Ninja Introduction to Amazon Simple Queue Service (SQS) HackerRank Certified Problem Solving Certificate AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials

Toni Gashi

Senior Software Engineer Bulgaria

Summary

Hi, my name is Toni and this is my journey.

I started professional web development after the first year of my Bachelor's degree as a software engineer for Greenterprise Media. The tasks were simple: Communicate with clients and fix the website (Javascript, CSS, HTML5). It was a small company, and the development team was composed of 2 people.

During my years at the American University in Bulgaria, I worked really hard, studying not only course material but also taking countless courses online. Eventually, I was frequently asked for help by my friends so I was already working as a tutor but then I decided to get paid for it so I was employed by the university to help my friends. The perfect job :D.

This was helping my friends but I thought I could do more. So I gathered the people I hung around with, who were also amazing programmers, and each of them had special skills and shared the idea of opening a club to help people who are struggling or want to further develop their skills. The response was amazing. That is how I became the Founder and the first president of "The Software Engineering Team". We were organizing discussions, programming competitions, projects, and other events, especially before COVID hit.

After it did, everything came to a halt. I decided to use this time to better myself and gain more experience, so I started working for a start-up called SeedStages. The work was fully remote and they were using some of the hottest technologies in the job market: React, Redux, etc.

In July 2021 the company decided to end its journey.

At this time, I had graduated with honors from AUBG so I was ready to get my first full-time job. I joined Re-Solutions and Sciant

(their partner) because I believed in their company culture and the technologies they were using were exactly what I wanted to do. AWS, React, NodeJS, etc. However, I also wanted to develop my career so I started working as a CTO for a startup that I and my friends created together Green Funds. The market research didn't work out great for us but it was an awesome experience with great people.

Then I joined DataDots where I worked heavily with React (mastered state management), Material-UI, tailwind, etc.

During my free time, I like going to the gym, playing soccer, pingpong, chess, watching FRIENDS (maybe some Big Bang Theory too) and learning about the latest tech trends.

I have currently received an AWS certification (CCP).

Currently I am working on mastering NextJS and Typescript.

If you made it this far, thank you so much for reading this.

Have an amazing day, Toni Gashi.

Experience

DataDots

Senior Software Engineer January 2023 - September 2023 (9 months)

Sofia, Sofia City, Bulgaria

Skills used: React, Javascript, Typescript, Front-End Development, Agile (SCRUM), REST APIs, Socket connections.

Sciant

Full-stack JavaScript Developer August 2021 - June 2022 (11 months)

Sofia, Sofia City, Bulgaria

Skills used: NodeJS, React, Javascript, Typescript, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Front-End Development, Back-End Development, NodeJS,

PostgreSQL, Docker, Agile (SCRUM), Hospitality Industry (mainly), REST APIs, Socket connections.

Green Funds

Chief Technology Officer and later Chief Executive Officer September 2021 - April 2022 (8 months)

Sofia, Sofia City, Bulgaria

We failed a start-up. This was an amazing chance to work with great people where we all learned from each other.

The goal we had in mind with this project was the increase of sustainability in Bulgaria and the education of the people on the importance that sustainability plays in the long run.

Seedstages

Frontend Developer January 2021 - July 2021 (7 months) California, United States

Skills used: Javascript, React Native, Git, Agile (SCRUM), Front end development,

The Software Engineering Team Founder February 2019 - January 2021 (2 years) Bulgaria

University club focused on hosting Coding Competitions as well as designing and developing software.

Organized a team of 15-25 members from different departments(marketing, programming competitions, project development, speakers) using the Scrum Framework to work together while focusing on Programming Competitions (using hacker-rank) and Project Development where we created dynamic websites that were user-friendly, effective, and appealing for the front-end as well as fluent in the back-end by following different design patterns.

Reputize

Online Reputation Consultant August 2020 - October 2020 (3 months)

London, England, United Kingdom

American University in Bulgaria Tutor of Fundamental Data Structures October 2018 - January 2020 (1 year 4 months)

Bulgaria

Had the opportunity to solidify my knowledge on the subjects covered by the course as well as other data structures while mastering teaching and learning the most useful ways of doing it.

The Black Dog Tavern, Co.
Retail Sales Specialist
May 2019 - September 2019 (5 months)
United States

- Received my Social Security Number.
- Monitored and maintained store inventory.
- Coached and supported new and existing Sales Associates.
- Communicated with clients and evaluated their needs.
- Handled complaints from customers.

Greenterprise Media Software Engineer Intern May 2018 - August 2018 (4 months) Tirana, Albania

- Implemented new languages with html5 to the virtual tour projects.

Please view our projects here (www.greenterprise.al)

- Communicated with clients and evaluated their needs.
- Was given additional work which I managed to complete.
- Improved operations by conducting systems analysis.

Education

American University in Bulgaria

Bachelor's degree, Mathematics and Computer Science (2017 - 2021)

Udemy

Computer Science, Unreal Engine C++ Developer: Learn C++ and Make Video Games · (2019 - 2019)

Turgut Ozal College

High School Diploma · (2014 - 2017)